The Horse Whisperer is a adventure, drama, romance
film directed by Robert Redford.
The mother of a severely traumatized daughter enlists the aid of a unique
horse trainer to help the girl's equally injured horse.
Tom Booker, played by Robert Redford.
Annie MacLean, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
Robert MacLean, played by Sam Neill.
Grace MacLean, played by Scarlett Johansson.
Diane Booker, played by Dianne Wiest.
Frank Booker, played by Chris Cooper.
The Horse Whisperer is a 1998 American neo-western drama film directed by and starring
Robert Redford, based on the 1995 novel The Horse Whisperer by Nicholas Evans.
Redford plays the title role, a talented trainer with a remarkable gift for understanding horses, who is hired to help an
injured teenager (played by Scarlett Johansson) and her horse back to health following a tragic accident.
The film was produced by Touchstone Pictures and released on May
15, 1998 by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed nearly $187 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of new york city, love triangle, attachment
to nature, parent child relationship, marriage crisis.
The tone is emotional.